So many people are starting jiu-jitsu at an older age, more now than ever before.
40's, 50's, even 60's, starting jiu-jitsu.
My father, for example, started at 64 years old, he's now 66 years old.
When you start older, you're not the athlete that you were when you were in your 20's and 30's.
You're not as flexible, you may not even be as strong, agile,
and it may even be harder to learn things.
Your brain might be just burnt out from just life and learning things.
So when my father told me he wanted to start training jiu-jitsu, he really wanted to get his blue belt.
So I understand the techniques that you need to learn to get your blue belt.
A lot of those techniques he wasn't able to do because of his lack of flexibility and just move overall movement.
He's been a carpenter for 40 years and his body's just kind of taken its toll.
So I was teaching him jiu-jitsu privately and he was taking classes, he was doing that each week.
So there was a lot of limitations, so I had to decide how to teach him and I had to relearn how to teach someone jiu-jitsu.
So I started extremely basic.
From this position, you need to be thinking this, this, and this.
And I kind of mapped out what is the jiu-jitsu jump-start blueprint.
So the jump-start blueprint helped him with what to do from every single position.
Knowing what to do when you're on the mount.
Knowing what the person on bottom of you is trying to think about doing.
And once you have that knowledge of every position, what you should be thinking and what they should be thinking,
jiu-jitsu becomes pretty easy.
Now you could take the techniques that you're learning in the intro curriculum
and you could actually apply them based on the strategies from each position.
It jump-started his learning and helped him get way better, way faster
and he's actually slated to get his blue belt this December, assuming everything goes to plan.
So if you're starting jiu-jitsu at a later age, 40s, 50s, 60s,
jiu-jitsu still is for you, you just have to do it the right way.
You have to be careful of who you're training with and you have to have more knowledge,
more strategies to combat the fact that your body isn't what it used to be
and your athleticism isn't what it used to be.
And I teach you the exact way on how to do that in the jiu-jitsu jump-start blueprint.
So click the link below or comment jump-start and you'll time-collapse your learning curve
and learn the strategies to help you combat those young bucks.